ALOK KUMAR

Sr. UX Designer

SUMMARY

Highly motivated Sr. UX designer with many years of experience in designing next-generation digital solutions. Team player to work on all stages of a product life-cycle, from initial sketches and low-res wireframes to high-res mockups and interactive prototypes.

With Human Centric & usability first approach I always strive for easy and simpler solution for end customer and also offer appealing and intuitive visuals that engage user with delightful experience.

EXPERIENCE

JUNE 2016 - PRESENT

Sr. UX Designer

HCL Technologies Ltd.

Design analysis and UX practices to produce reimagined and enhanced user experience for digital products/ services for global clients.

MAR. 2013 - MAY 2016

Team Lead UI/UX

Rapidsoft Technologies Pvt. Ltd.

Lead of creative team- responsible for design strategies, process evaluation and aesthetics. Integral part of projects with creative solutions on every phase of project being it ideation to marketing strategies.

JAN. 2012 - MAY 2013

Multimedia Designer

Des:Phi Studio

Graphic design for web and print, website, brand identity as logo, brochure and other branding accessories. Front end development for web portal- HTML/CSS and JavaScript.

MAY. 2011 - DEC 2011

Design Trainee

Ideafarms Pvt. Ltd.

Trained in design process, strategies and practices. Member of creative team- involved in brainstorming for product ideas. Wireframes, Design and Prototypes for web and mobile apps.

EDUCATION

MAR. 2013

HCI Certification

Interation Design Foundation

2008-2011

Bachelors in Animation & Design

Birla Institute of Technology, Mesra Ranchi (Noida Ext.)

KEY SKILLS

- User Centric Analysis and practices to ensure best in class experience to end customer
- Wireframes and prototypes for initial concept validation
- Interaction and communication Design
- Appealing and Intuitive Visuals Design
- Test and track user experiences, exploit possibilities of improvement
- Front end support to ensure design implementation

TOOLS (Latest Use)

- Sketchapp, Adobe Creative Suits
- Axure RP, Invision App, Principle

CONTACT

☑ alok22kr@gmail.com

+91- 991 199 3947

O Delhi NCR, India

LINKS

@ www.alokkumar.co.in

@its_allok

Bē www.behance.net/alokkr

in www.linkedin.com/in/alok22kr/

MAJOR CLIENTS

McKinsey&Company









